Standard Operating Procedure is a documentary,
war film directed by Errol Morris.
Errol Morris examines the incidents of abuse and torture of
suspected terrorists at the hands of U.S.
forces at the Abu Ghraib prison.
Self, played by Javal Davis.
Self, played by Ken Davis.
Self, played by Tony Diaz.
Self, played by Tim Dugan.
Self, played by Lynndie England.
Self, played by Jefferey Frost.
Standard Operating Procedure is a 2008 American documentary film written and directed by
Errol Morris that explores the meaning of the photographs taken by U.S.
military police at the Abu Ghraib prison in late 2003, the content of
which revealed the torture and abuse of its prisoners by U.S.
soldiers and subsequently resulted in a public scandal.
Commenting on the relationship of his film to the notorious photographs, Morris has said his intent was
"…not to say that these 'bad apples' were blameless… but… to say that they were scapegoats.
It was easy to blame them because, after all, they were in the photographs… Photographs don’t tell us who the real culprits might be… They
can also serve as a coverup, they can misdirect us… Photographs reveal and conceal, serve as [both] exposé and coverup".
The film explores themes of prison, prisoner,
photography, prison cell, jail guard.